# **Badia Grissa**

# **Gameplay Engineer**

Tunis, Tunisia | bediyagrissa@gmail.com | +(216) 56 180 295 | LinkedIn/me | GitLab

#### **SUMMARY**

Equipped with an extensive set of tools in Unreal Engine, I've advanced to the rank of Gameplay Engineer, creating pixel-perfect experiences that combine creativity and code. I've been in the digital space for two years and six months, and with my expertise in software engineering as my reliable ally, I'm always prepared for the next big battle: new chances and challenges. Together, let's build worlds where each line of code increases player immersion and opens up new creative opportunities.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **Gameplay Engineer (Unreal Engine)**

Jan 2022 - Present

Lanterns Studios (Tunis, Tunisia)

Utilizing Blueprint scripting, I developed most of gameplay logic.

Using C++ Coding when optimization is critical and a new feature must be introduced.

Optimizing Scenes that have too much polycount to improve FPS, using profiling tools to inspect scenes.

Using Animation Blueprint to make Character's animation cycle/states.

Utilizing Behavior Tree to develop NPC behavior.

Package/Export for VR and Desktop, fix bugs if there is any.

Utilizing Source Control tools to keep project healthy and easy to maintain or rollback.

Keywords: Unreal Engine 4/5, Blueprints, C++, Visual studio, perforce, VR, Multiplayer, Optimization, Debugging.

### **University Instructor**

Sep 2022 - Jan 2023

Higher Institution of Arts and Multimedia of Manouba (Manouba, Tunisia)

I taught C++ & Unreal Engine in university.

It was an introductory lesson for C++ then beginner level of Unreal engine using C++.

Keywords: C++, Visual studio, Unreal Engine, Debugging.

## **End of Studies Internship**

Feb 2021 - Aug 2021

Multi-Disciplinary International School (Sousse, Tunisia)

I worked on making base functionality for a rendering engine, to better understand how game engine works!

**Keywords**: Computer graphics, C++, Visual studio, OpenGL, GLM, GIT, GitLab, CMake, Optimization, Debugging.

#### **SKILLS**

- Blueprint scripting
- C++
- C#
- C
- Version control

- Unreal Engine 4/5
- Visual Studio
- Unity
- Adobe Illustrator
- Git

- Perforce
- OpenGL
- Network
- Blender
- Github/Gitlab

#### **EDUCATION**

### **Master of Software Engineering**

Multi-Disciplinary International School (Sousse, Tunisia)

### **Technician of Industrial & Automations in IT**

Professional Training Center of Sousse Section in Electronics (Sousse, Tunisia)

Sep 2016 – Sep 2021

Sep 2014 – Sep 2016

#### **VOLUNTEER WORK**

# Organizer and photographer

TCPC Tunisian Collegiate Programming Contest (Sousse, Tunisia)

I took photos during the event as part of the media team.

## **Head Organizer of Global Game Jam Sousse 2k23**

Gaming Freaks Tunisia (Sousse, Tunisia)

Feb 2023

Jun 2023

I was one of the head organizers of GGJ Sousse 2k23, I made sure the event goes as smooth as possible.

### Video editor (reels)

Dec 2022

ACPC Africa and Arab Collegiate Programming Championship (Sharm El sheikh, Egypt)

I was part of the media team in ACPC 2022, I made reels for the event.

### Organizer and photographer

Sep 2022

TCPC Tunisian Collegiate Programming Contest (Tunis, Tunisia)

I was part of the organizers for TCPC 2022, helped preparing the event and took photos during the event.

## **Extra-Activities**

- Founder of 2 University clubs
- Head in a Gaming Association (In opening phase).

### Languages

ArabicEnglishFrench